Zoom uses cookies on this site to improve performance, for analytics and for personalization. Please see our <u>Cookie Policy</u> for details and information on how to adjust your cookies settings. As a candidate for employment at Zoom, your personal data can be processed as described in our <u>Privacy Policy</u>.

Decline Accept Cookies

Accept Cookies

Sign In

Accept Cookies

Bearch for Jobs

2022 Full Stack Development Engineer (INTERN)

Apply

- Remote (CA) Bay Area
- Full time
- (L) Posted 19 Days Ago
- **■** R5739

Full Stack Software Engineer interns enable end-to-end and rich online experiences for Zoom products and projects. You will be matched to a Zoom engineering team responsible for designing, building, optimizing and deploying services for Zoom's technology ecosystem. This is a unique full stack internship opportunity to immerse in a complex and urgent software development life cycle.

Our Global Emerging Talent Intern Program offers additional support through dedicated mentorship, technical trainings, a leadership speaker series and team specific events. Ample time is dedicated to networking and plenty of fun. Come spend your summer learning and applying your technical smarts at Zoom!

What you will do:

- Write and push high quality code efficiently for both frontend and backend
- Build complex solutions in a fast-paced and collaborative environment
- Partner with cross-functional teams to understand, refine and implement product requirements
- Triage customer issues and provide technical solutions
- · Translate high-level roadmap vision into feasible feature specifications and deliverables
- · Participate in design and code reviews
- Fulfill our mission to *Deliver Happiness* through clean and elegant code

Requirements:

- Currently pursuing an undergrad or graduate degree in Computer Science, Computer Engineering or a related STEM field
- Available to complete the full 12-week internship program during Summer 2022, with a time commitment of approximately 40 hours per week.
- Some experience programming in at least two of the following: C++/C, Python, Java, JavaScript
- Knowledge of JS frameworks (i.e. React,, Angular, etc.) as well as responsive and adaptive web design principles

- · Solid baseline knowledge of data structures, algorithms, testing, and software design principles
- Understanding of fundamental web technologies including HTTP, HTML5, CSS, and RESTful web services
- Strong communication skills and a desire for continuous learning
- An authentic interest in supporting and advancing Zoom's mission, values, and culture

Please apply to no more than two Zoom Summer Internship roles

Ensuring a diverse and inclusive workplace where we learn from each other is core to Zoom's values. We welcome people of different backgrounds, experiences, abilities and perspectives including qualified applicants with arrest and conviction records as well as any qualified applicants requiring reasonable accommodations in accordance with the law.

We believe that the unique contributions of all Zoomies is the driver of our success. To make sure that our products and culture continue to incorporate everyone's perspectives and experience we never discriminate on the basis of race, religion, national origin, gender identity or expression, sexual orientation, age, or marital, veteran, or disability status.

All your information will be kept confidential according to EEO guidelines.

Explore Zoom:

- Hear from our leadership team
- Browse Awards and Employee Reviews on Comparably
- Visit our Blog
- Zoom with us!
- Find us on social at the links below and on Instagram













Charles Zhang

charleszhangmb@gmail.com ❖ (310) 739-0540 ❖ Los Angeles, CA ❖ czhangy.io

EDUCATION

University of California, Los Angeles

Sep. 2019 – Jun. 2023

B.S., Computer Science

Los Angeles, CA

- 3.92/4.0 GPA
- Organizations: ACM, Upsilon Pi Epsilon, Tau Beta Pi

PROFICIENCIES

- Skills: Front-end frameworks | Object-oriented programming | RESTful APIs | Data structures & algorithms | Agile methodologies | Leadership | Interpersonal communication
- Languages: C++ | JavaScript | HTML/CSS | Python
- Tools: Vue | React | Git | Node/Express | MongoDB | Linux | Unity | Microsoft Office | WordPress

WORK EXPERIENCE

Bruinshack Feb. 2021 – Present

Full-Stack Development Intern

Los Angeles, CA

- Designed and developed a responsive review system using Vue and the Vuex library that facilitates ratings and reviews from approximately 2,000 weekly active users looking for apartments in the Westwood area.
- Led a redesign of multiple static pages and the apartment manager portal in order to improve brand visibility and quality-of-life for the user base.

The Amplification Project

May 2021 – Sep. 2021

Front-End Developer

Los Angeles, CA

• Implemented a responsive design of the organization's main website using Vue while coordinating with a backend developer to raise awareness of forced migration through the preservation of related art and activism.

PROJECTS

DARS++ - (github.com/czhangy/darsplusplus)

Full-Stack Development

- Developed a full-stack web application using the MEVN stack that allows users to engage in course planning
 and attempts to optimize their upcoming schedule using topological sorting.
- Honed a user-friendly, responsive design on the frontend, while developing a simple RESTful API on the backend to practice database management through MongoDB Atlas.

BruinByte – (github.com/czhangy/bruinbyte)

Full-Stack Development

- Created and deployed a full-stack web application using React.js, designed to act as a local food review hub for UCLA students, based on the FERN stack.
- Integrated an authentication system and a dynamic ratings/comments system using Google Firebase.
- Learned various methods for communicating effectively within a team and building team chemistry.

Splekbot – (https://aaisara12.itch.io/splekbot)

Game Developer

 Led the level design team tasked with modelling 3D assets and levels using Unity ProBuilder to emphasize core gameplay mechanics, operating using Agile methodologies.